<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Chen</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Development - Date Posted and Chunk Coloring</title>
      <link>/post/website-development-date-posted-chunk-coloring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website-development-date-posted-chunk-coloring/</guid>
      <description>WIP - we are still actively working on making all code chunks more elegant.
Website improvements. While on one hand I want to switch to a theme more compatible with blogdown and R, I really like the overall theme. For now, we’ll treat this as an exercise in HTML, CSS, and JS.
For this post, we’ll make some small, yet meaningful quality of life improvements to our website. First, we’ll add the date posted for each post, and then fix the coloring of R code chunks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Exploration - First Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/python-exploration-first-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/python-exploration-first-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Note: Currently code chunks look better on desktop. We’re actively working on mobile support!
.standard {background-color: #f5f5f5;border: 1px solid #ccc;display: block;padding: 9.5px;margin: 0 0 10px;font-size: 13px;line-height: 1.42857143;word-break: break-all;word-wrap: break-word;color: black;width: 100%;}Three years ago I taught myself R to help process and visualize data for my research lab. Since then, I have easily spent hundreds, if not a thousand plus hours processing, modeling, visualizing, analyzing, tutoring, and struggling with the language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R - Overview of v1.0.0 of dtplyr and dplyr</title>
      <link>/post/r-dtplyr-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-dtplyr-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we discuss v1.0.0 of the dtplyr package and some changes made in the v1.0.0 update of dplyr. This post essentially summarizes these two posts:
dtplyr 1.0.0 - Hadley Wickhamdplyr 1.0.0 - Hadley WickhamAs these are two short, well-written posts, I highly recommend simply reading those two posts. If not, hopefully this post will inspire you to read them afterwards.
DtplyrSummaryIf you prefer dplyr syntax over data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R/Rstudio - Why Use Projects?</title>
      <link>/post/rstudio-why-use-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rstudio-why-use-projects/</guid>
      <description>The use of projects (.Rproj files) is fundamental to organized coding and project management, and should be used essentially 100% of the time while using RStudio. Thus in this post, we will discuss why you should use projects, how to create them, and some organization standards. We will also list a few additional resources for you to learn more about the subject at the very end.
Why Use It?In my opinion, there are four fundamental reasons why you should use projects:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Development - Highlighting Code Chunks</title>
      <link>/post/website-highlighting-code-chunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website-highlighting-code-chunks/</guid>
      <description>June 20th Edit: R Code Chunks were updated throughout the website automatically, so the coloring is slightly different. This post is maintained to show another way of changing the chunk features.
Whenever we need to include functional R code, whether it’s to check the output or just see how it was written, we include code chunks. Yet, currently on this website, it is extremely difficult to differentiate from the normal text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series - AR(1) Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/time-series-ar1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/time-series-ar1/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder that I am a student, and not a professional in the field. Please review the resources below before implementing the model. If there are any errors, please leave a comment/contact me and I will get it resolved immediately.
IntroductionTimes series. Simply put, when data is collected repeatedly over time, it often becomes a time series problem. It is extremely commonly used in academia and in industry, as this analysis can forecast future values, explain how the past influences the future, and highlight changes over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A/B Testing</title>
      <link>/post/a-b-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-b-testing/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder that I am a student, and not a professional in the field. Please review the resources below before implementing the model. If there are any errors, please leave a comment/contact me and I will get it resolved immediately.
IntroductionA/B testing. If you’re a student like me, you probably have never heard of it before in your statistics classes before. It sounds fancy. It sounds complex.
It’s neither of those.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Linear Modeling</title>
      <link>/post/hierarchical-linear-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hierarchical-linear-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder that I am a student, and not a professional in the field. Please review the resources below before implementing the model. If there are any errors, please leave a comment/contact me and I will get it resolved immediately.
IntroductionData often contains an inherent hierarchical nature, where some variables are nested within others.
A common example is student education. The data could be broken up into the following levels (example from (Woltman et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources to Learn R</title>
      <link>/post/resources-to-learn-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/resources-to-learn-r/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the school year, and especially while working as a statistical consultant, people would often ask me about how I learned to program in R. Since my answer of: “trial and error, practice, and classes” was insufficient for just about everyone, I wanted to compile a few resources here.
Just as a quick note, just about any programming experience will help you in R as well. Concepts in languages such as Python and Java will directly transfer over to R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 0 - 66 Days To Build A Habit</title>
      <link>/post/day-0-66-days-to-build-a-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-0-66-days-to-build-a-habit/</guid>
      <description>66 days.
In a 2009 study by Lally et al. (2009), researchers found that their study of 96 individuals took on average 66 days to truly form a habit. While the amount of time varied from 18 to 254 days, 66 gives us a definitive number to work towards.
Change has, and always will be difficult. It takes dedication, intention, and a commitment to breaking old habits, even when it becomes painful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Development - Google Analytics and Dark Mode (WIP)</title>
      <link>/post/website-updates-google-analytics-dark-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website-updates-google-analytics-dark-mode/</guid>
      <description>Google AnalyticsAs someone who adores stats, we of course need to set up stats for the website! Google analytics provides a free service that provides fairly detailed metrics on website performance. These statistics include:
Number of usersHow long users stay on the websiteHow users are acquiredUser retentionGeographical location of usersGeneral user behaviorSetup was extremely simple. After a quick registration where you provide the website URL and select privacy options, the google analytics account is created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Development - Initial Creation with Blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/website-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website-creation/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will explain how I created this website. This will include what resources I used, how I combined blogdown in R with GitHub Pages, and the various changes required for it to function correctly.
I will assume the user has already created a github.io page and linked GitHub and RStudio. I will assume familiarity with GitHub and R in general.
If the two assumptions are met, and the user does not spend too long choosing themes, the basic setup should not take more than 20 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me Welcome, my name is David Chen. Put simply, I love sharing statistics and analytics with those around me. Currently I work as a Research Assistant within the Statistics Department, and (during the academic year) as a research consultant for the Data Learning Center within the University Libraries. I will be graduating with my master&amp;rsquo;s in applied statistics and my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s in statistics (computer science option) in May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Connect with me on LinkedIn (davidchen17) while this page is under construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First snippet</title>
      <link>/snippets/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/snippets/first/</guid>
      <description>This content is in snippets/first/index.md
pwd </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second snippet</title>
      <link>/snippets/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/snippets/second/</guid>
      <description>This content is in snippets/second/index.md
ls -la </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>While this website is still under development, here we will list planned changes/posts.
Website  Dark/light mode button Clean back-end and extraneous folders/links Filter posts based on tags Comments Infinite scrolling for recent posts  Statistics!  Stochastic processes Analysis of likert-type scale data Multilevel/hierarchical models Time Series Bayesian spatiotemporal methods Gaussian Processes Cross-walking models  Insights / Data Viz TBD</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>