<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Website on David Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/website/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Website on David Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Development - Date Posted and Chunk Coloring</title>
      <link>/post/website-development-date-posted-chunk-coloring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website-development-date-posted-chunk-coloring/</guid>
      <description>WIP - we are still actively working on making all code chunks more elegant.
Website improvements. While on one hand I want to switch to a theme more compatible with blogdown and R, I really like the overall theme. For now, we’ll treat this as an exercise in HTML, CSS, and JS.
For this post, we’ll make some small, yet meaningful quality of life improvements to our website. First, we’ll add the date posted for each post, and then fix the coloring of R code chunks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Development - Highlighting Code Chunks</title>
      <link>/post/website-highlighting-code-chunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website-highlighting-code-chunks/</guid>
      <description>June 20th Edit: R Code Chunks were updated throughout the website automatically, so the coloring is slightly different. This post is maintained to show another way of changing the chunk features.
Whenever we need to include functional R code, whether it’s to check the output or just see how it was written, we include code chunks. Yet, currently on this website, it is extremely difficult to differentiate from the normal text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Development - Google Analytics and Dark Mode (WIP)</title>
      <link>/post/website-updates-google-analytics-dark-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website-updates-google-analytics-dark-mode/</guid>
      <description>Google AnalyticsAs someone who adores stats, we of course need to set up stats for the website! Google analytics provides a free service that provides fairly detailed metrics on website performance. These statistics include:
Number of usersHow long users stay on the websiteHow users are acquiredUser retentionGeographical location of usersGeneral user behaviorSetup was extremely simple. After a quick registration where you provide the website URL and select privacy options, the google analytics account is created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Development - Initial Creation with Blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/website-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website-creation/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will explain how I created this website. This will include what resources I used, how I combined blogdown in R with GitHub Pages, and the various changes required for it to function correctly.
I will assume the user has already created a github.io page and linked GitHub and RStudio. I will assume familiarity with GitHub and R in general.
If the two assumptions are met, and the user does not spend too long choosing themes, the basic setup should not take more than 20 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>